## **Gustavo Amigo**

System Architect | Full-Stack Software Developer

gustavo.amigo@gmail.com

## Summary

I'm a seasoned Full-Stack Developer. I have at least 12 years of working experience with software development in a wide spectrum of technologies like Java, JEE, C# .NET, Business Intelligence and C/C++. My current professional goal is to improve my knowledge on how to obtain, store, analyze and make data available to anyone in a fast and easy way. I have a quite successful experience deploying a full stack business intelligence solution to some clients using Microsoft Stack. I want to expand that experience with other Big Data technologies like Hadoop, Solr and NoSQL Database with Data Mining and Machine Learning Algorithm. I am also en enthusiast of algorithms and code problems, particularly Leetcode (https://oj.leetcode.com/) and Uva(http://uva.onlinejudge.org). I think that by studying algorithms and solving problems you become a better coder. Another subject that I have a lot of interest is Operating Systems, specially Linux.

## Experience

# System Architect | .NET | Business Intelligence | Cloud | AWS | Azure | Software Developer at Gera April 2012 - January 2015 (2 years 10 months)

System Architect working on many fronts like .NET and C# development, SQL Server, Business Intelligence with Analysis Services, Cloud with Azure and AWS, PHP (Joomla), MySQL and Linux. I also work as a tech adviser to the director board in order to help them make executive decisions.

1 recommendation available upon request

# $\label{localization} \textbf{Infrastructure and Operation Manager} \ | \ \textbf{AWS} \ | \ \textbf{Azure} \ | \ \textbf{.NET} \ | \ \textbf{PHP} \ | \ \textbf{Joomla} \ | \ \textbf{Zabbix at Gera}$ $\ \ \text{June 2012 - June 2013} \ \ (1 \ \text{year} \ 1 \ \text{month})$

\* Responsible to run Gera's operation and Infrastructure team of 4 to 5 professionals, managing around 80 servers across Latin America. \* Designed a new infrastructure architecture in order to reduce cost, reduce operation effort and boost performance \* Migrated most of our web instances that are built using Joomla to the Microsoft Stack (IIS, Windows 2008 R2 and SQL Server) \* Migrated our Monitor System (Zabbix) to a new version with many improvements to make it more reliable \* Deployed many internal services to AWS (EC2 e SES mainly)

#### System Architect | Java | Software Developer at Ci&T

August 2010 - May 2012 (1 year 10 months)

\* Responsible for a small team of software architects and software developers \* Software Development for Banking Systems, specially Credit management Systems \* Technologies: Java, JBoss, Sybase Database

## Software Development Coordinator | Java | Air Traffic Control | Linux | GIS | Software Developer at Atech Tecnologias Críticas

August 2008 - July 2010 (2 years)

\* Coordinated software development teams mainly for the Brazilian Armed Forces, especially the Brazilian Air Force. \* Coordinated a cross-functional team on the next version of the graphical user interface of the Air Traffic Management System used by all Brazilian Air Traffic Control Centers. \* Applied agile practices (Scrum) and PMI practices to boost quality and productivity towards business driven priorities. Past projects: \* Supporting system for electronic warfare for the Brazilian Air Force. \* Fragate simulator for for the Brazilian Navy. \* Most projects built using Java, C, GIS, Unix and integration with military and air traffic control equipment.

2 recommendations available upon request

## Software Designer | Tech Lead | Software Architecture | Java | JEE | Software Developer at Ci&T Software S.A.

February 2006 - July 2008 (2 years 6 months)

Software designer, team lead, and architect for projects using JEE technologies like EJB, JSP, JDBC and Web.

11 recommendations available upon request

#### Software Developer | JAVA | JEE at Ci&T Software

February 2004 - January 2006 (2 years)

Software developer working with JEE technologies like EJB, JSP, JDBC and Web.

## **Projects**

#### Nanoserver

February 2015 to Present

#### Members:Gustavo Amigo

This is a bare minimum implementation of an HTTP Server to serve static files. I created this project to study the basic features of node.js, while learning a little bit more about the HTTP protocol (see rfc7230). Therefore, it does not use the http module from node.js. So, you can say that this is reinventing the wheel, but that's what you do when you want to learn a little bit more about stuff.

#### Certifications

#### The Data Scientist's Toolbox

Coursera Verified Certificates License 3ZKC42F824 June 2014

#### **R** Programming

Coursera Verified Certificates License SUPB7HYCDZ June 2014

#### **Getting and Cleaning Data**

Coursera Verified Certificates License KDTEJ56GBR July 2014

#### **Exploratory Data Analysis**

Coursera Verified Certificates License UPXJ6QM2YM July 2014

#### **Statistical Inference**

Coursera Verified Certificates License 4F5VDV25VY February 2015

## Skills & Expertise

**Agile Methodologies** 

Scrum

**Software Development** 

**JBoss Application Server** 

**Java Enterprise Edition** 

Java

**Tomcat** 

**Design Patterns** 

**Software Engineering** 

**PostgreSQL** 

**Software Project Management** 

.NET

**Cross-functional Team Leadership** 

Microsoft SQL Server

**MySQL** 

**Windows Server** 

**Software Solution Architecture** 

IIS

**JavaScript** 

Linux

OOP

**C**#

**Typescript** 

**AngularJS** 

**Business Intelligence** 

## Languages

English(Native or bilingual proficiency)Portuguese(Native or bilingual proficiency)French(Limited working proficiency)

**Spanish** (Professional working proficiency)

#### Education

#### Universidade de São Paulo

Bachelor, Computer Science, 1998 - 2004

#### Interests

Cloud Computing, Big Data, Machine Learning and Data Minning, Reactive programming, Software Product Development, Business Intelligence, Software Development, Design Thinking, New Techhologies,

## **Gustavo Amigo**

System Architect | Full-Stack Software Developer

gustavo.amigo@gmail.com



## 14 people have recommended Gustavo

"Gustavo is an outstanding system architect, always thinking outside the box and bringing new technologies with practical application. Being a highly communicative, result-oriented and focused professional, it is always a pleasure to work with him."

### — Stefano Takamatsu Gioia, worked directly with Gustavo

"O Gustavo Amigo é um excelente Product Owner (P.O) competente e com sólida experiência em gerenciamento de equipes baseado no Scrum além de me incentivar o uso da "metodologia", como profissional ele é comprometido com os resultados e com o time que gere. Seu relacionamento com colegas, clientes e a empresa que ele veste a camisa comprova sua habilidade nos relacionamentos inter-pessoais. Excelente profissional recomendo a todos."

— João Dalben, Project Quality Plan, Atech, worked directly with Gustavo at Atech Tecnologias Críticas

"Gustavo has an impressive ability to lead teams. He is able to communicate in a very efficient and clear way and he knows how to keep all the team satisfied and motivated. He is highly result-oriented and very committed with quality in all projects."

— Mauro do Santo Junior, Development Analyst, Atech, reported to Gustavo at Atech

"Gustavo brings a rare combination of leadership, raw horsepower, knowledge and enthusiasm to his work. He's been a key contributor to every organization he's been a part of. I count myself very lucky to have had the privilege to work with him."

— Erika Nita Lotufo, PMP, CSM, Project Manager, Ci&T, worked with Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

"I do recommend Gustavo for any porpouse of Job contracts, He has shown outstanding work on every engagement he has played with. He might reach a good carreer at any Company he would be doing his best SVCastro"

— **Sebastião Ventura Castro**, *Sr Developer Mainframe & Scientific Languages, IBM Global Services*, worked directly with Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

"Gustavo is a great I.T. manager. He's able to balance between time pressure and product quality without losing the grip on any of them. He's also a very gentle person, the kind of you like to speak even when he's angry. However, even being a nice guy, he knows how to "steer" the team in the right direction wherever he needs it. He loves to solve hard problems and I saw he taking and solving a couple of them very calmly when everybody else is "freaking out". It was an excellent experience to work with him and I really hope we can work together again."

— **Ronie Uliana**, *Software Architect, Atech - Tecnologias Críticas*, reported to Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

"I had the opportunity to work with Gustavo a few years ago back in Brazil in our software architecture group. His strong technical skills, deep knowledge of programming and his ability do design complex software solutions make Gustavo a must have in a project!"

— **Felipe Rubim**, *Software Architect, Ci&T Software S.A.*, worked directly with Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

"Gustavo is a great professional, with a excellent technical knowlege and a great sense of team work. If you have Gustavo as member of your team you have security and a sign that your project will be a success."

— **Fabio Della Santina, PMP**, *Development Manager, Ci&T Software SA*, managed Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

"Gustavo brings solid technical skills, business sense and communication skills to any project he works on. He was a great help in communicating requirements and issues between our teams based in Brazil and the U.S. Gustavo exhibits passion and professionalism in his work."

- Chris Galli, Architect, Wirestone, managed Gustavo indirectly at Ci&T Software S.A.
- "O Gustavo é tipo de profissional focado e extremamente comprometido. Possui uma capacidade ótima de gerenciamento de projeto, bem como grande conhecimento de arquitetura. Grande profissional!"
- Taís Assad Della Santina, *Project Leader, Ci&T*, worked directly with Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

"Gustavo is one of th best Sotware Architect i've ever know. Excellent problem understanding and totally result driven professional. He has the abillity to structure a problem and design the best strategy to solve it. Also has excellent technical knowledge."

— **Willians Monteiro**, *SOFTWARE ARCHITECT*, *Ci&T*, worked directly with Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

"In the different projects I've worked with Gustavo - large and small - he always demonstrated great performance and excellent technical skills in Software Design and Architecture. Always close to new technology trends, Gustavo would bring valuable inputs to the team."

— Lucas Persona, Software Architect, Ci&T, worked directly with Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

"Gustavo is an eager software developer very concerned with the best quality and advanced technology application into software development. At that time, his differential was to delve into new technology and make it easy for his teamwork to use developing tutorials and models very easy to understand and use."

— Elisa Zaroni, Software Architect, Ci&T Software, managed Gustavo indirectly at Ci&T Software S.A.

"Gustavo é um profissional muito dedicado a tudo o que faz. Demonstra forte conhecimento nas áreas atuantes e desenvoltura na solução de problemas. Tem facilidade de comunicação e integração com a equipe e outros colaboradores da empresa."

— Marcelo Culen Jugdar, itil v3 f, rup 7.0, Engenheiro de Software, Ci&T, worked with Gustavo at Ci&T Software S.A.

Contact Gustavo on LinkedIn